cannot be easily damaged.
There are worse things in the world than being a Scarecrow end of Chapter 20
this is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain for more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay hall
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum chapter 21 The Lion Becomes the
King of Beasts After climbing down from the china wall the travelers found
themselves in a disagreeable country, full of bogs and marshes and covered
with tall, rank grass. It was difficult to walk without falling into muddy holes,
for the grass was so thick that it hid them from sight.
However, by carefully picking their way, they got safely along until they reached
solid ground. But here the country seemed wilder than ever, and after a long and
tiresome walk through the underbrush they entered another forest, where the
trees were bigger and older than any they had ever seen. “This forest is
perfectly delightful,” declared the Lion, looking around him with joy. “Never have I
seen a more beautiful place.” “It seems gloomy,” said the Scarecrow. “Not a bit of
it,” answered the Lion. “I should like to live here all my life.
See how soft the dried leaves are under your feet and how rich and green the
mosses that cleans these old trees.
Surely no wild beasts could wish a pleasanter home.” “Perhaps there are wild
beasts in the forest now,” said Dorothy. “I suppose there are,” returned the Lion, “but
I do not see any of them about.” They walked through the forest until it
became too dark to go any farther.
Dorothy and Toto and the Lion lay down to sleep, while the Woodman and the
Scarecrow kept watch over them as usual.
When morning came, they started again.
Before they had gone far they heard a low rumble, as of the growling of many wild animals.
Toto whimpered a little, but none of the others was frightened, and they kept
along the well-trodden path until they came to an opening in the wood, in which
there were gathered hundreds of beasts of every variety. There were tigers and
elephants and bears and wolves and Fox and all the others in the natural
history, and for a moment Dorothy was afraid. But the Lion explained that the
animals were holding a meeting, and he judged by their snarling and growling
that they were in great trouble. As he spoke several of the beasts caught sight
of him, and at once the great assemblage hushed as if by magic. The biggest of the
tigers came up to the Lion and bowed, saying: “Welcome, O King of Beasts! You have
come in good time to fight our enemy and bring peace to all the animals of the
forest once more.” “What is your trouble?” asked the Lion quietly. “We are all
threatened,” answered the tiger, “by a fierce enemy which has lately common to
this forest. It is a most tremendous monster, like a great spider, with a body
as big as an elephant and legs as long as a tree trunk. It has eight of these
long legs, and as the monster crawls through the forest he seizes an animal
with a leg and drags it into his mouth,
where it eats it as a spider does a fly.
Not one of us is safe while this fierce creature is alive, and we had called a
meeting to decide how to take care of ourselves when you came among us.” The
Lion thought for a moment. “Are there any other lions in this forest?” he asked. “No;
there were some, but the monster has eaten them all. And, besides there were
none of them nearly so large and brave as you.” “If I put an end to your enemy,
will you bow down to me and obey me as King of the Forest?” inquired the Lion. “We
will do that gladly return the tiger; and all the other beasts roared with a
mighty roar: “We will!” “Where is this great spider of yours now?” asked the Lion.
“Yonder, among the oak trees,” said the tiger, pointing with his forefoot. “Take
good care of these friends of mine,” said the Lion, “and I will go at once to fight
the monster.” He bade his comrades could buy and march proudly away to do battle
with the enemy. The great spider was lying asleep when the Lion found him, and
it looked so ugly that its foe turned up his nose and discussed Its legs were
quite as long as the tiger had said, and it's body covered with coarse black
hair. It had a great mouth, with a row of
sharp teeth a foot long; but its head was joined to the pudgy body by a neck as
slender as a wasp’s waist.
This gave the Lion a hint of the best way to attack the creature, and as he
knew it was easier to fight it asleep than awake, he gave a great spring and
landed directly upon the monsters back.
Then, with one blow of his heavy paw, all armed with sharp claws, he knocked
the spiders head from its body. Jumping down, he watched it until the long legs
stop wiggling, when he knew that it was quite dead. The Lion went back to the
opening where the beasts of the force were waiting for him and said proudly:
“You need fear your enemy no longer.” Then the beasts spout down to the Lion as